Name: Nathan Harris Position: Junior Software Engineer

Contact Details

Address: Bristol BS5/ Peterborough PE2 Email: nathan.harris.1@outlook.com
Phone: +44 7719118147 LinkedIn: /in/nathan-harris-engineer/
Portfolio: nathanharris.co.uk GitHub: github.com/nedd-ludd

Personal Brand Statement

I'm an Engineer at heart - I love making things work and fit together. Although starting with Civil Engineering, I used Python with GIS in my first job, and from then continued to apply this skill set wherever possible. Having seen the positive impact scripts and software could have, I took steps to grow these skills into a new career. With self-study, my own projects, volunteering, enrolling in a General Assembly Immersive Software course, and a large amount of dedication, I've equipped myself with a great range of current industry technical skills.

What I bring to the table is experience in STEM, years of working on complex projects, in diverse teams, but with the energy and excitement to take on a junior position in software engineering. My passion at its core is delivering solutions to problems, to the best possible quality, and within the constraints and requirements of our real world projects.

I am searching for a position in a company I can effectively partner with, where my commitment to the business is met with mentoring and opportunities to apply my skills in new and challenging environments.

Skills

Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SASS

Frameworks/ Libraries: Django, Django REST, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Material UI, Bulma, Tailwind, Next

Tools/ Platforms: Visual Studio Code, Chrome DevTools, Postman, Table plus, Mongodb Atlas

Soft: Communication, Teamwork, Work Ethic, Time management, Balancing time/cost/quality, Problem Solving,

Interpersonal Skills, Creativity, Adaptability

<u>Version Control:</u> Git, Github, GitBash <u>Spoken Languages:</u> English - Native, German-B1 intermediate

<u>Package:</u> Pip, pipenv, npm <u>Storage/ Cloud:</u> AWS, Cloudinary, Heroku, Netlify

Stacks: MERN Design/ Management: Excalidraw, Trello

Experience

Student Software Engineer, General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive - Remote

Training Organisation (November 2022- February 2023)

I completed a 12-Week intensive course focusing on Full-Stack development with the MERN stack and React.js with Python Django back-end. The course was delivered on Zoom and Slack, where I took part in daily standups, and individual, pair, and group coding projects, utilising Github for management and storage. I learnt the relevant languages, front to back end, frameworks, and tools necessary for full-stack development.

Final Project - "Ours"- a sharing economy app using separate Django REST for back-end and React/ MUI for the front-end. This was a fast paced solo 5-day project in which I produced a concept, developed the app and deployed live using Netlify and Heroku.

Link to Readme: bit.ly/3XTZ6XL Link to deployed project: bit.ly/3XTZ6XL

Group Project - "Adventure Map" - a review/ travel hot-spot site for curious adventurers using the MERN stack, enabling users to register and leave comments against any country. The project used the "simple-react-maps" package for an alternative site navigation. This was a 5-day group project where we used agile delivery and Git/GitHub to manage 3 team members' branched work before deploying online. My main role was back-end code and integrating the third party mapping package central to the site's objectives.

Link to Readme: bit.ly/3RqdpAJ Link to deployed project: bit.ly/3RqdpAJ

Previous Experience

Structural Engineer, JBA Consulting, Peterborough, Cambridgeshire

Civil/ Structural Engineering Consultancy

(May 2017- Present)

Key achievements: Project management, design and delivery of multi stakeholder schemes, managing and mentoring of graduates and technicians, with design checks and verification in line with briefs and standards.

Tester, Carecirle - Remote

Online Healthcare Platform

(November - December 2021)

Key achievements: Intro experience to devops, carrying out structured test plans for functionality against acceptance criteria using Microsoft Azure. Project involved reviewing purpose, and website/ program functionality. I carried out set actions and tested functionality, reporting any problems back to lead.

Design Engineer & Senior Technician, SLC Ltd, Lincolnshire, & SWH LLP Bedford/ London

Civil/ Structural Engineering Consultancies

(January 2014 – May 2017)

Key achievements: Huge array domestic / industrial scheme designs. Often tightly constrained projects, client facing, and short timescales. Produced long hand calculations or with software, and hand-sketches/ CAD drawings. Management ad-hoc teams, with costing and budget control showing adaptability across different sectors and project scales.

Education

AWS Cloud Practitioner - AWS, March 2023

JSE 40 Entry Level - Javascript Institute, February 2023

Software Engineering Immersive - General Assembly - November '22 - February '23

PCAP Certified Associate, Python Institute - *May 2022*

AZ-900: Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft - December 2021

HND Civil Engineering - Peterborough Regional College - Sept 2015 - June 2015

Analysing Spatial Data - ESRI UK - October 2010

Outside of work

Away from my desk, I love being outdoors practising bushcraft or doing open water swimming. I also spend a lot of time in my garage repairing cars or motorbikes.